<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<!-- descVersion 92 loads on every FS25 patch; this mod uses only launch-era
     schema. Bump to the current patch value (~106-107) to silence any notice. -->
<modDesc descVersion="110">
    <author>Bones</author>
    <version>1.1.0.0</version>

    <title>
        <en>Distribution Redux</en>
    </title>
    <description>
        <en><![CDATA[
Distribution Redux
Replace Farming Simulator 25's standard distribution system with a smarter, demand-driven logistics network.
Distribution Redux automatically moves resources between productions, animal husbandries, silos, and storages based on actual demand. It prioritises the nearest available source, supports automatic feed, straw, and water distribution, and gives you full control over how each output is handled.
Features

* No additional placeables required
* Works with existing productions, storages, silos, and animal husbandries
* Demand-driven distribution based on real consumption
* Automatic feed, straw, and water supply
* Multiple output modes: Hold, Distribute, Sell, Store, and combinations
* Hold Internal mode: keep bulk product in a production and spawn pallets on demand
* Proximity-based or whole-farm distribution
* Per-building and per-product configuration
* Multiplayer supported
Compatibility
Designed for the base game and compatible with most standard mods. Some custom buildings may require additional support.

Feedback/Issues: https://github.com/Bones50/FS25-Distribution-Redux

Changelog

v1.0.0.2
- Buildings can now be renamed: all buildings in the distribution network can be given a custom name from the base-game construction menu (silos, sheds and pits included, which the game does not normally allow). Distribution Redux uses that name throughout its menu, with the original building name shown beneath it as a reference.
- Fixed the Manure Heap and Slurry Pit listing each other's product: the Manure Heap now shows only Manure and the Slurry Pit only Slurry.
- Fixed the Manure Heap and Slurry Pit showing no incoming product; they now list what actually flows into them.

v1.0.0.1
- UI fixes and consistency edits.
- Added Markets and Kiosks to the distribution system.
- Fixed the sell-at-best-price logic that could sell too early on the first pass.
- Added the Hold Internal output mode: keep a production's bulk product in the building instead of auto-spawning pallets.
- Added manual pallet spawning from a Hold Internal output's held stock - a pop-up lets you pick the pallet type and quantity (capped by what's stored), available from the Distribution Redux menu and the base-game production screen.
]]></en>
        <de><![CDATA[
Distribution Redux
Ersetzt das Standard-Verteilungssystem von Farming Simulator 25 durch ein intelligenteres, bedarfsgesteuertes Logistiknetzwerk.
Distribution Redux transportiert Ressourcen automatisch zwischen Produktionen, Tierhaltungen, Silos und Lagern - basierend auf dem tatsächlichen Bedarf. Es bevorzugt die nächstgelegene verfügbare Quelle, unterstützt die automatische Verteilung von Futter, Stroh und Wasser und gibt dir die volle Kontrolle darüber, wie jede Ausgabe gehandhabt wird.
Funktionen

* Keine zusätzlichen Platzierungsobjekte erforderlich
* Funktioniert mit vorhandenen Produktionen, Lagern, Silos und Tierhaltungen
* Bedarfsgesteuerte Verteilung auf Basis des tatsächlichen Verbrauchs
* Automatische Versorgung mit Futter, Stroh und Wasser
* Mehrere Ausgabemodi: Hold, Distribute, Sell, Store und Kombinationen
* Modus "Hold Internal": Schüttgut in der Produktion behalten und Paletten bei Bedarf erzeugen
* Näherungsbasierte oder hofweite Verteilung
* Konfiguration pro Gebäude und pro Produkt
* Mehrspieler wird unterstützt
Kompatibilität
Entwickelt für das Grundspiel und kompatibel mit den meisten Standard-Mods. Einige benutzerdefinierte Gebäude erfordern möglicherweise zusätzliche Unterstützung.

Feedback/Issues: https://github.com/Bones50/FS25-Distribution-Redux

Changelog

v1.0.0.2
- Gebäude können jetzt umbenannt werden: Alle Gebäude im Verteilungsnetz lassen sich über das Baumenü des Grundspiels mit einem eigenen Namen versehen (auch Silos, Schuppen und Gruben, was das Spiel sonst nicht erlaubt). Distribution Redux verwendet diesen Namen im gesamten Menü und zeigt den ursprünglichen Gebäudenamen darunter als Referenz an.
- Fehler behoben, bei dem Misthaufen und Güllegrube jeweils das Produkt des anderen anzeigten: Der Misthaufen zeigt nun nur noch Mist, die Güllegrube nur noch Gülle.
- Fehler behoben, bei dem Misthaufen und Güllegrube kein eingehendes Produkt anzeigten; sie listen nun das, was tatsächlich hineinfließt.

v1.0.0.1
- UI-Korrekturen und Konsistenzanpassungen.
- Märkte und Kioske zum Verteilungssystem hinzugefügt.
- Fehler behoben, bei dem "Zum besten Preis verkaufen" beim ersten Durchlauf zu früh verkaufte.
- Neuer Ausgabemodus "Hold Internal": Das Schüttgut einer Produktion im Gebäude behalten, statt automatisch Paletten zu erzeugen.
- Manuelles Erzeugen von Paletten aus dem gehaltenen Bestand eines "Hold Internal"-Ausgangs - ein Dialog erlaubt die Auswahl von Palettentyp und Anzahl (durch den Bestand begrenzt), verfügbar im Distribution-Redux-Menü und im Produktionsbildschirm des Grundspiels.
]]></de>
    </description>

    <iconFilename>icon_DistributionRedux.dds</iconFilename>

    <multiplayer supported="true"/>

    <l10n>
        <text name="input_DISTREDUX_OPEN_DIALOG">
            <en>Configure distribution (nearest asset)</en>
        </text>
        <text name="input_DISTREDUX_OPEN_MANAGER">
            <en>Open Distribution Redux menu</en>
        </text>
    </l10n>

    <actions>
        <action name="DISTREDUX_OPEN_DIALOG" category="BASE"/>
        <action name="DISTREDUX_OPEN_MANAGER" category="BASE"/>
    </actions>
    <inputBinding>
        <actionBinding action="DISTREDUX_OPEN_DIALOG">
            <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_leftbracket"/>
        </actionBinding>
        <actionBinding action="DISTREDUX_OPEN_MANAGER">
            <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_backslash"/>
        </actionBinding>
    </inputBinding>

    <extraSourceFiles>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/DistributionLimits.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/DistributionModeEvent.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/DistributionSellTimingEvent.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/DistributionMarketTimingEvent.lua"/>
        <!-- Seasonal price-curve reader for best-price selling (pure reader; loaded early). -->
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/DistributionPricing.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/SmartDistribution.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/DistributionSettings.lua"/>
        <!-- 4th production output mode "Distribute + Sell".
             Remove this line + scripts/ProductionDistributeSell.lua to disable. -->
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/ProductionDistributeSell.lua"/>
        <!-- Help-content source (topic text + word-wrap) reused by the menu's User Guide tab.
             The old keybind-opened help popup is retired; ] now opens that tab instead. -->
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/DistributionHelpDialog.lua"/>

        <!-- Consolidated full-screen menu (TabbedMenu) with left-side tabs:
             Productions / Silos / Animal Husbandry / User Guide / Settings.
             Base page class loads first, then the page subclasses, then the menu screen. -->
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/gui/DistributionMenuPage.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/gui/DistributionSettingsPage.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/gui/DistributionStoragePage.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/gui/DistributionProductionsPage.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/gui/DistributionHelpPage.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/gui/DistributionSpawnDialog.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/gui/DistributionAdvancedDialog.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/gui/DistributionInputsDialog.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/gui/DistributionMenu.lua"/>
    </extraSourceFiles>
</modDesc>
